Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/idboehman (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Bash

Python

Java

Languages

Spanish (Elementary)

Isaac B.

Senior Software Engineer

San Francisco Bay Area

Summary

Highly motivated with a focus on getting things done. Enjoy self learning and research and am generally quick to pick things up.

My main interests are backend, operations/system administration and information security.

Specialties

Systems: Linux (Debian/Red Hat), OS X, and Windows

Languages: Python, Ruby, Bash, Go, Java

Software: AWS/GCP, PostgreSQL, SCM (Git)

GitHub: https://github.com/yacn

Experience

Cloudflare

Senior Software Engineer

April 2022 - Present (1 year 6 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

Area 1 Security

Software Engineer - Development Operations January 2018 - March 2022 (4 years 3 months)

Redwood City, CA

DNS, Python, Java, Go, Docker, Chef, Packer, Terraform, Jenkins,

Kubernetes, Kafka, Datadog, distributed/remote teams.

BitSight Technologies

Operations Engineer

June 2016 - September 2017 (1 year 4 months)

Cambridge, MA

- Led operations and containerization efforts across multiple feature teams
- Migrated company to Docker for local development environments
- Increased feature teams' efficiency via templated Flask+Postgres microservice app
- Researched and chose Kubernetes as next evolution of engineering infrastructure
- · Worked with remote teams in Lisbon, Portugal and Raleigh, NC

Facebook

Production Engineer Intern July 2015 - November 2015 (5 months)

Menlo Park, CA

Team: Data Infrastructure Compute - Batch Analytics

 Built and improved Python scripts to associate system metrics with Hadoop pipelines

on a per-cluster basis called DistributedTop.

- · Added features to internal JNI perf agent in C
- Improved internal failure monitoring tool in Python

BitSight Technologies Operations Engineer May 2013 - May 2015 (2 years 1 month) Cambridge, MA

I put the Ops in DevOps

- Built infrastructure orchestration framework enabling developer access to resources via common language (Python)
- Established best practices for developing and testing Chef cookbooks in a standard development environment involving linting (Rubocop, Foodcritic), unit tests (ChefSpec), and integration tests (Test Kitchen via Docker with ServerSpec)
- Expanded use of Sensu for metrics and alerting, focused on democratizing metrics/alerting across developers and operations.
- Created Python tool to automate data processing job configuration
- Implemented Django back end for two customer-facing product features
- Improved Ruby-based internal server provisioning tool via bug fixes and new features
- Wrote security policy documents to set company-wide standards
- Debugged Hadoop clusters and other assorted fire-fighting
- Migrated company from Chef Server 10 to Chef Server 11

• Automated new user provisioning process for OS X and Ubuntu.

Northeastern University

1 year 11 months

ResNet System Administrator

September 2012 - May 2013 (9 months)

Boston, MA

- Managed users and computers via Active Directory, Puppet, and nagios
- Implemented IDS for detection of threats against the office

ResNet Computer Technician

July 2011 - May 2013 (1 year 11 months)

Boston, MA

- Diagnosed and repaired software and hardware problems on all types of computers
- Performed warranty part replacement for Dell and Apple machines
- Contributed to in-office projects to create an efficient work space
- Obtained CompTIA A+ certification

Marco's Pizza

Delivery Driver

June 2011 - July 2012 (1 year 2 months)

Fishers, Indiana

- Delivered pizza to customers promptly, safely, and efficiently
- Provided excellent customer service

Pyle's Pools

Lifeguard

June 2010 - June 2011 (1 year 1 month)

Fishers, Indiana

- · Maintained and ensured safety of customers
- Vigilantly watched over patrons to ensure their safety
- Enforced rules and regulations of the pool

Education

Northeastern University

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), Computer Science and Information Science · (2011 - 2016)

Activity

04/05/2022, Viewed by Fabio Haring

09/13/2023, Viewed by Joeri Leemans